Daniel C. Dennett Papers MS138
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Correspondence, circa 1970 -- 2017; MS138.003; 16.25 Linear Feet; 7 Digital Object(s)
  - Correspondence and drafts, MS138-036 (Box 29)
    Content and Consciousness correspondence; drafts of my ENS lectures (in French) in Paris. ?year?; draft of a paper delivered at Bolt Baranek and Newman, in 1977 or maybe 76; Ryle correspondence; Quine correspondence; Edelman correspondence; extra black book with various unpublished papers in it; correspondence with GEO, German version of Sci Am., re debate with Steven Rose.
  - Correspondence A-J email directories, 2009 -- 2012; MS138-042
  - Correspondence, 2011 -- 2012; MS138-043 (Box 30)
  - March 2012 email, MS138.002.060; 1 Digital Object(s) Comprises 3,746 emails.; 500 Megabytes
    MS-2019-086
    This material is likely duplicative.
  - Correspondence, 2012 -- 2013; MS138-044 (Box 31)
  - Email correspondence, 2006 -- 2014; MS138.002.045; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 zip file containing 101 mbox files.; 6.18 Gigabytes
    101 mbox files from Daniel Dennett. Zip file includes spreadsheet listing indiviual files.
  - Email correspondence, 2010 -- 2015; MS138.002.046; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 zip file containing 78 mbox files.; 1.96 Gigabytes
    78 mbox files from Daniel Dennett. Zip file includes spreadsheet listing individual files.
  - Written correspondence, FY2014, and Intuition Pumps manuscript, circa 2012, MS138-047 (Box 32)
  - Email correspondence, 2015 -- 2016; MS138.002.052; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 zip file containing 187 mbox files.; 3.85 Gigabytes
    187 mbox files from Daniel Dennett. Zip file includes spreadsheet listing individual files.
  - Correspondence FY2015, 2014 -- 2015; MS138-055; .25 Linear Feet (Box 33)
    Transferred by Teresa Salvato, 2016, accession MS-2017-017.
  - Correspondence FY2016, 2015 -- 2016; MS138.002.056; .25 Linear Feet (Box 56)
    Transferred by Teresa Salvato, 2017, accession MS-2018-007.
  - Email correspondence, circa 2016; MS138.002.057; 4.28 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 zip file containing 99 mbox files.
  - Correspondence, FY2017, 2016 -- 2017; MS138.000771; 8 Folder(s) (Box 68)
  - Email correspondence, 2017; MS138.002.059; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 zip file containing 101 mbox files.; 8.3 Gigabytes
- 2018 accessions, circa 1989 -- 2012; MS138.004; 9 Linear Feet; 19 Digital Object(s); 8.6 Megabytes
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This series may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  Gift of Daniel Dennett, 2018, accession MS-2019-040 and MS-2019-086.
  This series contains drafts and other writings, correspondence, research and subject files, and VHS and cassette tapes and CDs and DVDs featuring Dan Dennett or his work. This series also contains Dennett's March 2012 email.
  - "Consciousness Explained" drafts and related correspondence, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.060; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 60)
    Writings are open for research. Corresponendence is closed until Dennett's death. This file may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - "Darwin's Dangerous Idea" drafts and related correspondence, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.061; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 61)
  - Subject files, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.062; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 62)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and subject files, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.063; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 63)
  - Media appearances on VHS and VHS collection, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.064; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 64)
  - Media appearances on VHS and VHS collection, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.065; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 65)
  - Media appearances on VHS and cassette and VHS and cassette collection, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.066; 0.6 Linear Feet (Box 66)
  - Media appearances on CD and DVD and CD and DVD collection, circa 1989 -- 2009; MS138.004.067; 1.2 Linear Feet (Box 67)
    This file is open for research, but is minimally processed and may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
  - Musical lecture, 1992--1998; MS138.004.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.08 Megabytes
    Open for mediated access due to rights issues.
  - Emails, notes, CV, and mailing lists, 1995--1997; MS138.004.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.25 Megabytes
  - Munich, philosophy March 1999, 1998--2000; MS138.004.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.49 Megabytes
  - Emails and notes, 1998--1999; MS138.004.00004; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.44 Megabytes
  - Notes and drafts, 1990--1998; MS138.004.00005; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.37 Megabytes
  - Emails, letters of recommendation, and notes, 1998--1990; MS138.004.00006; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.06 Megabytes
  - Notes and quotes, 1989--1999; MS138.004.00007; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.09 Megabytes
  - Syllabus and Notes, 1993--1993; MS138.004.00008; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.45 Megabytes
  - Emails and letters of recommendation, 1988--1989; MS138.004.00009; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.58 Megabytes
  - Emails and drafts, 1989--1989; MS138.004.00010; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.58 Megabytes
  - Notes, 1990--1993; MS138.004.00011; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.33 Megabytes
  - Notes and Dennett family personal papers, 1990--1999; MS138.004.00012; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.3 Megabytes
    Open for research. This item may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for more information.
  - Cope paper draft, 1979--1999; MS138.004.00013; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.03 Megabytes
  - Paintbrush files, 1988; MS138.004.00014; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.42 Megabytes
    Open for mediated access due to format. This item may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for more information.
  - Notes, drafts, and communications, 1980--1999; MS138.004.00015; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.3 Megabytes
  - Notes and bibliography, 1991--1994; MS138.004.00016; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.2 Megabytes
  - Conference notes, 1987--1988; MS138.004.00017; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.01 Megabytes
  - Notes, drafts, and recommendations, 1980--1999; MS138.004.00018; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.3 Megabytes
  - Poetry and photos, 1980--1999; MS138.004.00019; 1 Digital Object(s); 1.3 Megabytes
- Curriculum vitae, 1965 -- 2019; MS138.005; 9.91 Megabytes; 34 Digital Object(s)
  Transferred by Teresa Salvato, 2019, accession MS-2020-053.
  This series contains Daniel Dennett's curriculum vitae.
  - Curriculum vita, 1965; MS138.000734; 126 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1970; MS138.000735; 227 Kilobytes
  - Career narrative, 1972; MS138.000736; 151 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1974; MS138.000737; 121 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae and information for annual report, 1976; MS138.000738; 631 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1979; MS138.000739; 400 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1981; MS138.000740; 525 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1982 January; MS138.000741; 236 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1982 June; MS138.000742; 262 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1983 November; MS138.000743; 331 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1983 November; MS138.000744; 357 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1984; MS138.000745; 417 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1984 -- 1985; MS138.000746; 270 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1984 February; MS138.000747; 232 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1984 November; MS138.000748; 340 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1985 May; MS138.000749; 545 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1989 March; MS138.000750; 504 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 1993 June; MS138.000751; 393 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2001; MS138.000752; 215 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2002; MS138.000753; 213 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2002 September 19; MS138.000754; 162 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2003; MS138.000755; 207 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2006; MS138.000756; 153 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2008; MS138.000757; 160 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2008 April 30; MS138.000758; 124 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2009; MS138.000759; 317 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2010 March 30; MS138.000760; 311 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2013 March 5; MS138.000761; 428 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2013 May; MS138.000762; 369 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2014; MS138.000763; 384 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2014; MS138.000764; 191 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2015 April 17; MS138.000765; 378 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2017; MS138.000766; 190 Kilobytes
  - Curriculum vitae, 2019 April 29; MS138.000767; 269 Kilobytes
- 2020 accessions, circa 1991 -- 2020; MS138.000768; 50.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 51 files.
  Access to this series is restricted.
  Transferred by Teresa Salvato, accession MS-2021-027.
  This series is arranged in the order in which it was received.
  This series contains publications written by Daniel Dennett.
  - Daniel C. Dennett publications, circa 1991 -- 2020; MS138.000769; 50.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 51 files.
- 2022 accessions, 1994 -- 2022; MS138.000772; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 14 files.; 16.7 Megabytes
  Transferred by Teresa Salvato, 2022, accession MS-2022-046.
  - Daniel C. Dennett publications, 1994 -- 2022; MS138.000773; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 14 files.; 16.7 Megabytes